export const JEWELLERYA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The rank of a commissioned officer in the army is identified by the use of",
A: "bangles.",
B: "epaulette.",
C: "brooch.",
D: "amulet.",
answer: "B. Epaulette",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Alloying in jewellery involves",
A: "fusing metals.",
B: "purifying metals.",
C: "adding two metals.",
D: "joining metals.",
answer: "A. Fusing metals",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Diamond as a jewellery material is classified as",
A: "synthetic.",
B: "organic.",
C: ". artificial,",
D: "inorganic.",
answer: "D. Inorganic",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Select the most precious gemstone from the options.",
A: "Agate",
B: "Pearl",
C: "Topaz",
D: "Amber",
answer: "B. Pearl",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Symbols are best cut in the centre of metal plates by",
A: "sawing.",
B: "filing.",
C: "piercing.",
D: "punching.",
answer: "C. Piercing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. An attribute required for effective Jewellery fabrication is",
A: "patience.",
B: "observant.",
C: "leadership.",
D: "confidence.",
answer: "A. Patience",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Choose the prestigious function of wearing beads from the options.",
A: "Protection",
B: "Identification",
C: "Communication",
D: "Healing",
answer: "B. Identification",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The visitors book at an exhibition helps the jeweller to",
A: "interact with guest.",
B: "attract customers.",
C: "improve sales.",
D: "assess performance.",
answer: "D. Assess performance",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Select a major setback to the development of the precious jewellery industry in Ghana.",
A: "High cost of advertisement",
B: "Poor power supply.",
C: "Lack of affordable loans",
D: "Low patronage of items",
answer: "C. Lack of affordable loans",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. A disjointed gold chain is repaired by using",
A: "pliers.",
B: "scriber.",
C: "triblet.",
D: "tweezer.",
answer: "D. Tweezer",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. In appreciating a jewellery item, the physical qualities are described under",
A: "inventory of items.",
B: "identification.",
C: "technical qualities.",
D: "interpretation.",
answer: "C. Technical qualities",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Traditionally, a jewellery witha seagull image symbolizes",
A: "victory.",
B: "peace.",
C: "hope.",
D: "love.",
answer: "C. Hope",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Stone beads are associated with",
A: "Abompe.",
B: "Nkawkaw.",
C: "Somanya.",
D: "Nungua.",
answer: "C. Somanya",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Traditionally, casting is done by using",
A: "bamboo mould.",
B: "cuttlefish bone.",
C: "tortoise shell.",
D: "leatherhard clay slab.",
answer: "B. Cuttlefish bone",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The reasons for conducting market survey for jewellery includes:\nI. knowing consumerâ€™s preference,\nII. determining target groups,\nIII. increasing demand,\nIV. finding out current prices.",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I, II and IV only",
C: "IlI and IV only",
D: "I, III only",
answer: "B. I, II, and IV only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Identify the prectous metal from the options..",
A: "Copper",
B: "Silver",
C: "Brass",
D: "Bronze",
answer: "B. Silver",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The layout of a jewellery workshop should be planned to",
A: "ensure a strong structure.",
B: "avoid waste of materials.",
C: "ensure effective use of space.",
D: "expand the production process.",
answer: "C. Ensure effective use of space",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Spilled oil on the studio floor is dangerous because it may cause",
A: "irritation.",
B: "scalds.",
C: "corrosion.",
D: "accidents.",
answer: "D. Accidents",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. A glass bead mould should be coated with kaolin to",
A: "avoid cracking of beads.",
B: "reduce the melting point of beads.",
C: "make removal of beads easy.",
D: "increase the firing temperature of beads.",
answer: "C. Make removal of beads easy",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. A pickled copper bangle exposed to dampness over a period will develop",
A: "mildew.",
B: "patina.",
C: "spirogyra.",
D: "verdigris.",
answer: "B. Patina",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The major reason for preliminary designs in jewellery production is to",
A: "enhance the beauty of the work.",
B: "ensure precision and finishing.",
C: "exhibit artistic skills.",
D: "promote sales of items.",
answer: "B. Ensure precision and finishing",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Select the most appropriate tool for cutting bamboo when making beads.",
A: "Knife",
B: "Cutlass",
C: "Hacksaw",
D: "Snippers",
answer: "C. Hacksaw",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Identify the metallic property of metal that facilitates heat transmission",
A: "Ductility )",
B: "Conductivity",
C: "Malleability",
D: "Fusibility",
answer: "B. Conductivity",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. In preparing glass beads colour is added at the",
A: "sieving stage.",
B: "pounding stage.",
C: "moulding stage.",
D: "firing stage.",
answer: "B. Pounding stage",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Select a decorative technique for enhancing clay beads.",
A: "Burnishing",
B: "Incising",
C: "Lacquering",
D: "Firing",
answer: "B. Incising",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Ivory is obtained from",
A: "tusks.",
B: "hooves.",
C: "horns.",
D: "bones.",
answer: "A. Tusks",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Select the technique best used for decorating organic jewellery material.",
A: "Pickling",
B: "Scorching",
C: "Buffing",
D: "Enamelling",
answer: "B. Scorching",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Identify a costume jewellery item from the options.",
A: "Quartz pendant",
B: "Platinum bracelet",
C: "Gold necklace",
D: "Sapphire ring",
answer: "A. Quartz pendant",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Surfaces of cuttlefish bone are sanded flat to be",
A: "properly domed.",
B: "handled easily.",
C: "properly aligned.",
D: "less weighty.",
answer: "C. Properly aligned",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Choose the most suitable device for annealing a pair of earrings.",
A: "Gas burners",
B: "Soldering rod",
C: "Blow torch",
D: "Furnace",
answer: "C. Blow torch",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The part of the body which is usually decorated with an epaulette is the",
A: "shoulder.",
B: "neck.",
C: "ankle.",
D: "knee.",
answer: "A. Shoulder",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Choose the best pair of forming tools used for enlarging a finger ring.",
A: "Planishing hammer and triblet",
B: "Hide mallet and mandrel",
C: "Wooden mallet and mandrel",
D: "Ball pein hammer and triblet",
answer: "B. Hide mallet and mandrel",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Select the property which enables metals to withstand abrasion.",
A: "Fusibility",
B: "Workability",
C: "Hardness",
D: "Streak",
answer: "C. Hardness",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. A thick wire can be made thin by",
A: "pickling.",
B: "etching.",
C: "milling.",
D: "heating.",
answer: "C. Milling",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. In the fabrication of a wire necklace, the most important tool is",
A: "blade.",
B: "scriber.",
C: "pliers.",
D: "dividers.",
answer: "C. Pliers",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Select the object that is used for mass production of jewellery items.",
A: "Mould",
B: "Armature",
C: "Shell",
D: "Crucible",
answer: "A. Mould",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The cutting side ofa file is called",
A: "kerf.",
B: "teeth.",
C: "handle.",
D: "tang.",
answer: "B. Teeth",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Select the most appropriate process for making dry clay workable.",
A: "Pounding, sieving, soaking and kneading.",
B: "Pounding, soaking, sieving and kneading.",
C: "Soaking, sieving, wedging and kneading.",
D: "Soaking, wedging, drying and kneading.",
answer: "C. Soaking, sieving, wedging, and kneading",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. In beadmaking, glass is fired to become",
A: "vitrified.",
B: "porous.",
C: "solid.",
D: "diffused.",
answer: "A. Vitrified",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Effective packaging of a gold finger ring helps to",
A: "improve designs.",
B: "promote creativity.",
C: "enhance product.",
D: "improve quality.",
answer: "C. Enhance product",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]